>> Brian Holt: 我希望您尝试输入此内容。
&gt;&gt; Brian Holt: I want you to try and
type into this.
>> Brian Holt: 恭喜，您打破了 DOM。
&gt;&gt; Brian Holt: Congratulations,
you broke the DOM.
这其实挺难做的对吧
This is actually kinda difficult to do,
right?
[ LAUGH] 这是人们第一次出现的挫折感
[LAUGH] And this is one of people's
frustrations when they first
学习写 React 就像以前这么简单
learn to write React is like,
this was so simple to do before.
我们为什么要做些简单的事情
Why did we make something simple hard?
对，说的是有效的。
Right, it's a valid thing to say.
但我想让你想想这事是怎么运作的
But I want you to think
about how this works.
每当我在这里输入某样东西
Whenever I type something in here, so
如果我现在按下一个按键，会发生什么 " 反应 " 会捕捉到这个事件。
if I hit a keystroke right now,
what happens is React captures that event.
然后，它的组件中的再渲染循环会发生什么。
Then what happens is that kicks off a
re-render cycle inside of its components.
所以，第一个发生的事情是重新呈现应用程序。
So the first thing that
happens is it re-renders app.
然后它做了一个 SearchParams ，它会跳到搜索参数中。
And then it gets done a SearchParams and
it hops down into search params.
这里说的是公寓等于西雅图华盛顿
Here, it says const location
equals Seattle, Washington.
它重新呈现，这个输入的价值是什么 ?
And it re-renders, and what is
the value of this input right here?
西雅图对吧
Seattle, right?
没什么变化对吧
Nothing changes that, right?
所以当它重新呈现时，仍然是西雅图的原因，因为什么都没有改变。
So when it re-renders again, it's still
Seattle's because nothing changed it.
所以这就是为什么，即使我在那里，也没有改变。
So that's why, even when I type in there,
it's not changing.
那么换句话说，
So in other words,
两种数据绑定在 React 中不可用，这可能是一个沮丧的问题。
two way data binding is not free in React,
which can be a point of frustration.
我以前是个角开发商
I used to be an Angular developer.
我在 Reddit 工作的时候写了很多角度
I wrote a lot of Angular
when I worked at Reddit.
这对我来说是令人沮丧的，因为这对我来说是自由的，对吧 ?
So this was frustrating for me because
this used to be free to me, right?
如果是在 Angular就像他那样做了什么
If, in Angular, just did the NG bind or
something like that and
它只是结合在一起工作和魔法
it was just bound together and
it worked and magical.
这已经不是我的问题了我要为此辩解
That's no longer the case and
I'm gonna argue for that.
这其实是个好处因为它迫使我
It's actually a benefit
because it forces me to
想想那些正在发生的事情
think through everything that's happening.
我不再受限于这个框架会为我做什么。
And I'm no longer limited by what
the framework is gonna do for me.
我必须这样做，我认为这是一个好处，因为后来
I have to do it,
which I think is a benefit because later,
当我回到它的时候我可以读读所有正在发生的事情对吧
when I come back to it, I can read
everything that's happening, right?
我不需要特别了解你的角度，或者我不需要知道什么是 " 超级好 "
I don't have to know Angular super well or
I don't have to know React super well to
知道发生了什么，因为我可以看到所有规范的代码。
know what's happening because I can
see all the code that's governed.
这是非常明确的。
It's very explicit.
这实际上只是一种一般的反应趋势。
This is actually kind of just
a general trend for React.
很详细，对吧 ?
It's verbose, right?
您编写更多代码。
You write more code.
这可能是一个沮丧的问题。
And that can be a point of frustration.
但我认为这其实是 React 最大的好处之一
But I argue that this is actually
one of the biggest benefits of React
因为这是可以理解的对吧
because it's very understandable, right?
它迫使你思考一切
It forces you to think through everything.
这意味着当你一个月后回来的时候你可以重新阅读
Which means that when you come back to
this a month later, you can re-read all
你写的代码明白发生了什么好吗
the code that you wrote and
understand what's happened, okay?
因此，我们希望现在能从西雅图， WA 改变到其他事情。
So we want to be able to change this
now from Seattle, WA to something else.
那么我们要怎么做呢 ?
So how are we going to do that?
那我们来看看吧
Well, let's take a look at that.
>> Brian Holt: 在此处，显示导入 React 的位置
&gt;&gt; Brian Holt: Up here,
where it says import React, for
我我要用逗号了
me, I'm gonna put comma, .
然后我要从雷法进口
Then I'm going to import that from React.
> > Brian Holt: 因此，我要在这里说，
&gt;&gt; Brian Holt: So instead of having
this location here, I'm gonna say const,
方括号，位置，逗号和 setLocation。
square bracket, location,
comma, setLocation.
= useState，然后是缺省状态，即西雅图， WA，
= useState, and then the default state,
which is gonna be Seattle, WA,
>> Brian Holt: 好吗 ?
&gt;&gt; Brian Holt: Okay?
现在，我在此输入中有此位置。
Now, I have this location in this input.
你可能注意到的事情
The thing you might notice,
如果你看这里的控制台，如果我看着控制台，它大概会说，
if you look at the console here, if I look
at the console, it's probably gonna say,
您在没有非更改处理程序的情况下向表单提供了值属性。
you provided a value prop to a form
without a non-change handler.
这就是原因
That's why.
我们要给这个改变处理程序
We're going to give this
a on change handler.
所以我想说改的是花括号
So I'm gonna say on change = curly braces.
我要给它一个小小的功能当一个事件发生时就能运行
I'm going to give it just a tiny function
to run whenever an event happens.
所以我想说只要有一件事
So I'm gonna say,
whenever there is an event,
setLocation 为 e.target 值。
setLocation to be e.target value.
所以这有点有点
[BLANK AUDIO] So this is a little,
小小的功能对吧
little tiny function, right?
它只需要一个活动，所以你可以在那里举办活动，
And all it does it it takes an event,
so you can actually put event there,
如果这让你感觉更好
if that makes you feel better about it.
我只是养成了一个永远的习惯
I just have a habit from
forever that I call events e.
>> Brian Holt: 您可以决定这对您是否有用。
&gt;&gt; Brian Holt: You can decide
if that's useful to you or not.
>> Brian Holt: 如果您已为 jQuery 编写事件处理程序，或者
&gt;&gt; Brian Holt: And if you've ever
written an event handler for jQuery or
就是普通的 JavaScript ，应该是熟悉的，对吧 ?
just normal JavaScript,
that should look familiar, right?
这是一个正常的事件处理程序。
It's a normal-looking event handler.
>> Brian Holt: 另一个问题是，如果您有一行函数
&gt;&gt; Brian Holt: And the other thing is
if you have a single line of a function
使用箭头函数，花括号是可选的。
with an arrow function,
the curly braces are optional.
所以我可以把它放进去，然后它看起来也一样，也很好。
So I could put that, and then it would
look like that, which is fine as well.
>> Brian Holt: 那么现在，任何在此输入中发生更改的时间，
&gt;&gt; Brian Holt: So now, any time that
a change happens in this input,
它会用输入中的任何东西来调用 setLocation 。
it's gonna call setLocation with
whatever is inside of the input.
所以现在如果我回到这里我就开始在这里打字
So now if I go back over here and
I start typing in here,
它就会重新开始工作
it's gonna start working again.
为什么呢
Now, why?
我输入的是重新呈现程序搜索参数重新呈现程序
Well, I type, it kicks off a reRender,
search param reRenders.
然后我把这两件事情都在这里，地点和位置。
And then I have these two things up here,
location and setLocation.
位置将会是位置的当前状态，好吗 ?
Location is going to be the current
state of location, okay?
然后，设置位置是该特定状态的更新程序。
And then set location is an updater for
that particular piece of state.
所以每次那个事件发生的时候，对，我就在里面，
So every time that that event happens,
right, that I type into there,
E 将表示输入中发生的事件。
E is going to represent an event
that happened in the input.
然后我就会打电话给 setLocation
And then I'm gonna call setLocation
with whatever is inside
在那个特定事件中或者在输入的内部
of that particular event,
or inside of that input,
就是要更新我的状态好吗
which is going to update that
state that I'm getting here, okay?
那么当这种重新出现的时候
So then,
when that re-render happens after that,
无论我把它更新成什么样的位置
location is going to now be
whatever I've updated it to be.
现在可以让我感到困惑了，我这里有个字符串，华盛顿西雅图。
Now it can be a little confusing that I
have this string here Seattle, Washington.
很明显那是不改变的
And obviously, that's not changing, but
请记住，这始终是缺省状态，对，第一个状态。
just keep in mind that this is always
the default state, right, the first state.
然后在那之后，它就会成为当时的一切。
And then after that, it'll be
whatever it is at that point in time.
但那是你必须谨记的是
But that's, you have to keep in mind
that that's what happens with these
这些组件的功能是它们运行了很多次，对吗 ?
render functions for these components
is they're run a bunch of times, right?
每次更新应用程序时，它都将重新运行所有呈示。
Every time that you update your
application, it reruns all of the renders.
因此，您希望确保这些功能未在执行
So you want to make sure that
these functions are not doing
什么外来的，对吗 ?
anything extraneous, right?
他们不应该更新任何功能。
They shouldn't be updating any function.
他们不应该有任何类似的副作用
They shouldn't have any like side
effects or anything like that.
你要把它们的重点放在渲染的焦点上，好吗 ?
You want to keep them pretty narrow to
the focus of rendering something, okay?
这是一个钩子，这就是反应术语的存在。
So this is a hook,
that's what the react terminology is here.
还有一件事，你需要遵守钩子，所有钩子都开始使用。
And one thing that you need to abide by
with hooks, all hooks begin with use.
使用状态，使用效果，使用回调，使用备忘录，
Use state, use effect,
use callback, use memo,
所有这些钩子都开始使用了
all that stuff, all hooks begin with use.
即便是定制挂钩之类的
Even the ones like custom hooks,
我们要做一个定制的钩子 [ COUGH]
we're going to make a custom
hook [COUGH] excuse me.
我们要在这里做个定制的钩子
We're going to make a custom
hook here in just a second.
但如果你看到有什么用的话，它是一个钩子。
But if you see use something,
it is a hook.
这就是你的有状态逻辑与 React 有这些挂钩的方式。
So this is how you have stateful
logic with React is with these hooks.
所以现在任何时候都要向你证明
So now at any given time,
just to demonstrate to you,
我就说一个 console.log('state )
I'll just say a console.log('state
位置，位置 )。
of location', location).
>> Brian Holt: 或者更好，我们来做吧。
&gt;&gt; Brian Holt: Or
even better, let's do this.
我们就放个 h1 吧
Let's just put an h1 right here.
>> Brian Holt: 在其中有位置。
&gt;&gt; Brian Holt: That has location in it.
>> Brian Holt: 现在它说西雅图， WA 在那儿，对吧 ?
&gt;&gt; Brian Holt: So now it says Seattle,
WA right there, right?
如果我们开始打字，就会发现它正在和
And if we start typing in there,
notice that it's changing alongside of,
因为每当它重新呈现的时候，它就会输出到那个位置。
because every time it re-renders, right,
it's outputting that location there.
所以我可以把盐湖城放在犹他州
So I could put Salt Lake City, Utah.
>> 扬声器 2: 在此上下文中使用状态与设置状态不同，
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Is using state different
than setting state in this context,
那就因为它设定了一个默认值，就在这里。
then, because it's setting a default,
out of the box here.
>> Brian Holt: 是的，那么使用状态就像创建一个挂钩，对吧 ?
&gt;&gt; Brian Holt: Yes, so
useState is like creating a hook, right?
所以，当你回来的时候，你会得到一系列的东西。
So and, when you get back a hook,
you get back an array of two things.
第一件事永远是它的现状。
The first thing is always going
to be the current state of it.
第二件事始终是一个更新的功能
The second thing is always going
to be an updater function for
那个特殊的说法，对吧 ?
that particular piece of statement, right?
因此 useState 会创建挂钩。
So useState creates the hook.
这被称为集合地点，因为我选择这样称呼它，但是
This is called set location because
I chose to call it that, but
您可以完全调用此 updateLocation。
you could totally call
this updateLocation.
它的功能使您能够支持特定事物的更新。
It's a function that gives you back
the updates that particular thing.
我选择总是叫它，因为我可以看到它，但是
I choose to always call it set
because then I can kind of see it, but
这只是我的约定
that's just a convention that I have.
这不是行业最佳做法。
That's not an industry best practice or
anything like that.
这能回答你的问题吗
Does that answer your question?
太酷了
Cool.
我应该打电话给你这对你来说有点怪
I should call out here,
this might look a little weird to you.
这也是一种破坏性的，对，因为我知道这会是一个数组。
This is also destructuring, right,
because I know this is gonna be an array.
这始终支持数组。
This always gives back an array.
我知道第一个项目总是国家
And I know that the first
item is always the state, and
我一直知道第二个项目是 " 更新者 " 功能。
I always know the second item
is the updater function.
这就是为什么这是一个阵列。
So that's why that's an array.
有道理吗
Makes sense?
太酷了
Cool.
> > Brian Holt: 在历史上，如果你一直在写 " React" ，
&gt;&gt; Brian Holt: So historically,
if you've been writing React,
你就得用所谓的 " 设定 " 状态对吧
you would have had to use
something called set state, right?
这就取代了对这些功能组件的设置状态的需求。
This is kind of supplanting the need for
set state for these function components.
我再给你看看怎么做
I will show you later how to do that
因为重要的是它仍然是重做生态系统的一部分
because it's important cuz it's still
very much a part of the React ecosystem.
但现在，这就是用钩子做状态的方法。
But for now,
this is the way to do state with hooks.